Guide to the CONSOL Energy, Inc. Mine Maps and Records, 1857-2010 AIS.1991.16
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Photographic and Media Materials, 1912-1997; XXI.
  - FIATT Mine (Box 295, Folder 14)
  - West Virginia, Ceredo Mine and Docks (Box 295, Folder 15)
  - Jenner Mine/ Power Plant ca. 1919 (Box 295, Folder 16)
  - Ireland Mine ca. 1956 (Box 295, Folder 17)
  - Shamrock Mines Nos. 1 & 2 (Box 295, Folder 18)
  - DISCO- Distilled Coal ca. 1949-1953 (Box 295, Folder 19)
  - Flood Photos ca. 7/25/1969 - 7/29/1969 (Box 295, Folder 20)
  - Mining Shovels (Box 295, Folder 21)
  - Miners In Action" ca.1948-1968 (Box 295, Folder 22)
  - Burning Star Mine No. 1 (Box 295, Folder 23-24)
  - Burning Star Mine No. 2 (Box 295, Folder 25-26)
  - Burning Star Mine No. 2, Mining Shovel (Box 295, Folder 27)
  - Burning Star Mine No. 3 (Box 295, Folder 28)
  - Mining Equipment, ca. 1919-1968 (Box 295, Folder 29-30)
  - Kayford, Leewood, and Rose Mines (Box 295, Folder 31)
  - Raccoon and Ceredo Mines (Box 295, Folder 32)
  - Administrative Staff and Company Receptions (Box 296, Folder 1-3)
  - Coal Breaker- Shenandoah, PA (Box 296, Folder 4)
  - Consol Published Advertisements (Box 296, Folder 5)
  - Panorama of Unknown Mining Town, ca. 1940s (Box 296, Folder 6)
  - Pittsburgh Consolidation Coal Co. Management ca. 1958 (Box 296, Folder 7)
  - Jake Ke(p?)ler (Box 296, Folder 8)
  - Ribbon Cutting Ceremony near Steubenville, OH, November 22, 1961 (Box 296, Folder 9)
  - Unknown Canadian Mine and Wash Plant, ca. 1980s (Box 296, Folder 10)
  - First Aid Teams and First Aid Competitions, ca. 1946-1960s (Box 296, Folder 11-12)
    Prints depicting first aid demonstrations and competitions sponsored by the coal mining industry, and the mining rescue teams that participated in them. The history of such gatherings dates to October 30, 1911 when the first national mine-safety demonstration was held at Forbes field, in Pittsburgh. The demonstration was planned and managed by engineers of the Bureau with the aid of miners and coal operators of the Pittsburgh district. It embraced exhibits that demonstrated the character of nearly every branch of the Bureau's investigative work in relation to mine accidents, including first-aid and mine-rescue work, coal-dust explosions, and also special coal-dust explosions at the Bureau's experimental mine at Bruceton, Pa. Approximately 15,000 persons attended the demonstration. Thenceforth, first aid contests were annually held in mining towns across the Appalachians and mining country.
  - Textual Documents (Box 296, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Negatives- 4x5 (Box 296, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Negatives- 35mm (Box 296, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Negatives- Transparencies (Box 296, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Prints (Box 296, Folder 17)
  - Bishop Mine Prep Plant, (just beginning demolition activities- Sept. 1996) (Box 297, Folder 1)
  - Bucyrus – Erie, Backhoe fire at B.S. No. 4 (Box 297, Folder 2)
  - Buchanan Prep Plant Superintendent- Tom Burton (Box 297, Folder 3)
  - Miners Vacation- Picture Page, Contractor Connection Newsletter. Ca. 1998 (Box 297, Folder 4)
  - Photos of the Newly Completed Fine Coal and Briquetting Plant Located at the Robena Preparation Plant Site, ca. 1998-2000 (Box 297, Folder 5)
  - Matthews Mines (Nos. 1, 2, 3) (Box 297, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Prints (Box 297, Folder 7)
  - DISCO Promotional Zippo Lighter (no fluid) (Box 297, Folder 8)
  - Vinyl pressings (2) of assorted mining songs (Box 298, Record 1-2)
- Union Coal and Coke Company Maps, 1899-1968; XXII.
  This series primarily includes maps, plans and technical drawings relating to mines and buildings owned and operated by the Union Coal and Coke Company in eastern Washington County, Pa. There are also some maps, plans and technical drawings relating to mines owned and operated by the Ellsworth Collieries Company and other coal operators near those of the Union Coal and Coke Company. Additionally, there are maps of towns and property associated with all of these mines.
  - Proposal from Roberts and Schaefer Co. for Mine No. 58, Marianna, Pa., 1952 (Box 285, Folder 44)
  - Union Coal and Coke Company plat book, 1918 (Map-case 09-15, Folder 7)
  - Municipality and property maps, 1908-1962 (Map-case 09-15, Folder 8)
  - Railroad track maps and wiring plans, 1901-1959 (Map-case 09-15, Folder 9)
  - Coal field maps, 1917-1922 (Map-case 09-15, Folder 10)
  - Technical drawings, 1904-1968 (Map-case 09-15, Folder 11)
  - Building plans, 1899 (Map-case 09-15, Folder 12)
  - Maps, plans and technical drawings, 1906-1919 (Roll 344)